Spencer Cindia



| LinkedIn | (330) 605-1806 | spencer.cindia@gmail.com | Cleveland OH |

Experienced entrepreneur with a professional background in music production and database-related technologies spanning more than a decade. Continually elevating a career in software development. Possesses a love for learning and bringing the perspective of a technical and collaborative musician to a development team.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python

Frameworks and Technologies: Spring Boot, Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js

Data: JSON, XML, XSLT Databases: PostgreSQL

Cloud Technologies: AWS, Anypoint

Version Control: Git

Testing: Unit Testing (JUnit), Integration Testing

Tools: IntelliJ, Unix, Splunk

Other: REST, ActiveMQ, Responsive Design, E/R diagrams

Education

Tech Elevator Grad | Jun 2022

Graduate of a 14-week full-stack coding bootcamp learning how to create dynamic web-based software systems using Java providing 700+ hours of development education and application.

Professional Experience

Accenture

Packaged App Development Analyst (Promoted 2023)

2022 - Present

- Maintain and extend API integrations using Mulesoft, for smooth data flow and integration.
- Test integrations on a local environment using dummy payloads for reliability.
- Monitoring incidents and requests through ServiceNow.
- Investigating message processing errors due to 400/500 responses.
- Automate manual tasks using Python to improve efficiency.
- Assessing queue depth and consumers, vertical scaling during peak retail activity.
- Collaborate closely with a tight-knit team to delegate CI/CD operations, ensuring smooth deployment and continuous delivery.
- Actively involved in Agile-based project development, collaborating in a dynamic environment for quick adaptability and iterative growth.

Self-Owned Music Production Business

Founder, Musician, Audio Engineer

2018 - 2022

- Methodical signal flow (i.e. line/XLR in and out (plus console inserts), patchbay flow, AD/DA
- Collaborated with artists to create diverse live sound and production techniques
- Mix and Master on various consoles and in the box using reductive EQ philosophy
- Production and composition in Ableton, Logic, and ProTools

Liberty Ford

Inventory Control, Shipping & Receiving

2015 - 2018

- Managed \$500,000 approximate valuation of parts inventory
- (Promotion 2017)
- Coordinated with internal departments and external vendors to schedule shipments
- Independently learned CDK inventory database software to streamline inventory control
- Worked with national Ford parts warranty deposition for proper processing of warranty claims
- Followed all HAZMAT and OSHA protocols, as well as forklift certified